{
  "questionModals": [
    {
      "question": "Who gave the name 'Sagarmatha' to World's highest peak Mt. Everest?",
      "answers": [
        "Som Nath Sigdel",
        "Chakrapani Chalise",
        "Lekhnath Poudel",
        "BabuRam Acharya"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "When was Children's day was observed First time in Nepal?",
      "answers": [
        "16th Falgun 2016 BS",
        "16th Falgun 2018 BS",
        "18th Falgun 2016 BS",
        "18th Falgun 2018 BS"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Almost all the rivers of Nepal flows from North to South but one river flows from South to North. Name the river.",
      "answers": [
        "Indrawati River",
        "Karmanasha river",
        "Uttar Ganga River",
        "Likhu River"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Name the Malla king who introduced copper coin in Nepal.",
      "answers": [
        "Ratna Malla",
        "Mahindra Malla",
        "Pratap Malla",
        "Siddhi Narsingha Malla"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first Prime Minister after 2007 BS Democracy?",
      "answers": [
        "Mohan Shumsher",
        "B.P. Koirala",
        "Matrika Prasad Koirala",
        "Tanka Prasad Acharya"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the only athlete to bring Olympic medal to Nepal, a bronze medal?",
      "answers": [
        "Sita Rai",
        "Bidhan Lama",
        "Sangina Baidhya",
        "Baikuntha Manandhar"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Name the first woman Ambassador to other country from Nepal.",
      "answers": [
        "Binu Lohani",
        "Manchhura Devi",
        "Brinda Shah",
        "Preksha Singh"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Where is the oldest bell and drum of Nepal situated?",
      "answers": [
        "Gorkha Palace",
        "Bhaktapur Durbar Square",
        "Lalitpur Durbar Square",
        "Kathmandu Durbar Square"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "First man to be awarded 'Tribhuwan Puraskar'.",
      "answers": [
        "Nara Bahadur Bharati",
        "Bala Krishna Sama",
        "Laxmi Prasad Devkota",
        "Bhim Nidhi Tiwari"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Name the first Nepali film in colour.",
      "answers": [
        "Sindur",
        "Kumari",
        "Juni",
        "Paral ko Aago"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Where is the tallest bridge of Nepal?",
      "answers": [
        "Manthali, Ramechhap",
        "Jiri, Dolakha",
        "Modikhola, Parvat",
        "Sindhuli"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What portion of the world is occupied by the wetland?",
      "answers": [
        "5.9%",
        "6.2%",
        "10%",
        "3%"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "How many places of Nepal have been declared wetlands (simsar) now?",
      "answers": [
        "Six",
        "Seven",
        "Eight",
        "Nine"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "When did Tul Bahadur Pun, a Victoria Cross winner, pass away?",
      "answers": [
        "9 Baishakh, 2068",
        "7 Baishakh, 2068",
        "26 Baishakh, 2068",
        "12 Baishakh, 2068"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "What has the government of Nepal declared to observe the year 2010 AD as?",
      "answers": [
        "violence against dowry",
        "violence against sex",
        "violence against murder",
        "violence against crime"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the artist to create world record by filling colour on a 123 m long canvas on a single day?",
      "answers": [
        "Tilochan Gautam",
        "Rabindra Manandhar",
        "Tilak Manandhar",
        "Kiran Manandhar"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "With an objective of conserving the culture and tradition of the Tamang people, where was the Tamang Museum established?",
      "answers": [
        "Taplejung",
        "Rasuwa",
        "Kaski",
        "Mananag"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the conservation area first established in Nepal?",
      "answers": [
        "Annapurna Conservation Area",
        "Makalu Barun Conservation Area",
        "Koshi Tappu wildlife",
        "Chitwan National Park"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "When was the Amali system eradicated?",
      "answers": [
        "1964 BS",
        "1968 BS",
        "1963 BS",
        "1965 BS"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "From which did music originate?",
      "answers": [
        "Yajur Ved",
        "Rigz Ved",
        "Sama Ved",
        "Ramayan"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What’s the most important book in the Muslim religion?",
      "answers": [
        "The Quran",
        "The Dictionary",
        "The Bible",
        "The Chemistry text Book"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "What’s the capital of Ethiopia?",
      "answers": [
        "Cape Town",
        "San Francisco",
        "Abuja",
        "Addis Ababa"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 3 
    },
    {
      "question": "Into how many categories is the land classified on the basis of productivity?",
      "answers": [
        "5",
        "4",
        "6",
        "2"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the father of Rana Prime Minister Mohan Shumsher?",
      "answers": [
        "Chandra Shumsher",
        "Juddha Shumsher",
        "Dev Shumsher",
        "Padma Shumsher"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "According to the Muluki Ain 2020, what was the maximum interest rate allowed in Nepal?",
      "answers": [
        "14%",
        "13%",
        "10%",
        "12%"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 2
    },
  
    {
      "question": "In which district is the ‘Fungfung’ waterfall?",
      "answers": ["Nuwakot", "Rasuwa", "Sindhupalchok", "Kapilvastu"],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "How many heritage properties are listed in the World Heritage List?",
      "answers": ["7", "13", "15", "10"],
      "correctIndex": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first to use the word ‘Jai Nepal’?",
      "answers": [
        "Prithvi Narayan Shah",
        "Shukraraj Shastri",
        "Bhimsen Thapa",
        "Girija Prasad Koirala"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "How many national pride projects are there in Nepal right now?",
      "answers": ["15", "20", "23", "25"],
      "correctIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What percentage of the total land area of Nepal is cultivated on land?",
      "answers": ["17.97%", "14.83%", "16.24%", "19.35%"],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is Nepal’s first highway?",
      "answers": [
        "Prithvi Highway",
        "Araniko Highway",
        "Tribhuvan highway",
        "Karnali Highway"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of road Kathmandu – Pokhara?",
      "answers": [
        "Tribhuvan Highway",
        "Prithwi Highway",
        "Araniko Highway",
        "Mahendra Highway"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "What is called the blank sheet on the front and back of the book?",
      "answers": ["Cover", "Endpaper", "Fly Leaf", "Title Page"],
      "correctIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the ‘Zero’ Inventor?",
      "answers": ["Aryabhata", "Brahmagupta", "Bhaskara I", "Varahamihira"],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "From which district did tea cultivation originate in Nepal?",
      "answers": ["Dhankuta", "Ilam", "Jhapa", "Panchthar"],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "When was the division of 14 zones and 75 districts?",
      "answers": [
        "2016 Baishakh 01",
        "2017 Baishakh 01",
        "2018 Baishakh 01",
        "2019 Baishakh 01"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "How many MW of electricity has been produced in Nepal so far?",
      "answers": ["1024 MW", "1142 MW", "1268 MW", "1386 MW"],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "When is earthquake day celebrated in Nepal?",
      "answers": ["Magh 1", "Magh 3", "Magh 4", "Magh 2"],
      "correctIndex": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "In which district does the Chinamasta’s temple belong?",
      "answers": ["Saptari", "Siraha", "Sunsari", "Udayapur"],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "What is is called Tharu caste the ‘Ghar-Jwai’ in tradition?",
      "answers": ["Jharu", "Bhyawarpaithana", "Parakhi", "Rajbanshi"],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Which district lies in Zakhira Lake?",
      "answers": ["Bardiya", "Dang", "Kapilvastu", "Rupandehi"],
      "correctIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "By what name is the Bhandarkal festival known?",
      "answers": [
        "Basnet Parwa",
        "Ghode Jatra",
        "Indra Jatra",
        "Shikali Jatra"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },

    {
      "question": "Which is the smallest district of Nepal after local level division?",
      "answers": ["Bhaktapur", "Kathmandu", "Lalitpur", "Sindhupalchok"],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Where is the ‘Ghorne’ waterfall?",
      "answers": ["Bhojpur", "Dhankuta", "Sankhuwasabha", "Tehrathum"],
      "correctIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Where did Gautam Buddha give the first sermon?",
      "answers": [
        "Bodh Gaya, India",
        "Kushinagar, India",
        "Lumbini, Nepal",
        "Sarnath, India"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the second Miss Nepal of Nepal?",
      "answers": [
        "Sumi Khadka",
        "Sadichha Shrestha",
        "Shweta Singh",
        "Malvika Subba"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the first Chairman of the Public Service Commission?",
      "answers": [
        "Anirudra Prasad Singh",
        "Bhesh Bahadur Thapa",
        "Durga Prasad Pandit",
        "Bishnu Prasad Shrestha"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the tallest temple in Nepal?",
      "answers": [
        "Guheswari Temple",
        "Janaki Temple",
        "Muktinath Temple",
        "Pashupatinath Temple"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "By what treaty did the First World War end?",
      "answers": [
        "Treaty of Brest-Litovsk",
        "Treaty of Versailles",
        "Treaty of Trianon",
        "Treaty of Saint-G"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a country with no police and no prison?",
      "answers": ["Sweden", "Norway", "Denmark", "Iceland"],
      "correctIndex": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the hottest place in the world?",
      "answers": ["Libya’s Azizia", "Death Valley", "Dasht-e Lut", "Tirat Zvi"],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the only district not getting fish in Nepal?",
      "answers": ["Darchula", "Manang", "Mustang", "Dolpa"],
      "correctIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the nation with the most borders in the world?",
      "answers": ["China", "Russia", "India", "Brazil"],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Which country is ruled by two presidents?",
      "answers": [
        "Switzerland",
        "Andorra",
        "Bosnia and Herzegovina",
        "Sanmarino"
      ],
      "correctIndex": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is known as the birthplace of World Cup football?",
      "answers": ["Julius Rimet", "France", "Italy", "Uruguay"],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "In which district is Gosikund located?",
      "answers": ["Dhading", "Dolakha", "Rasuwa", "Nuwakot"],
      "correctIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Which mountain of Nepal is considered as the basis for authentic time?",
      "answers": ["Everest", "Kangchenjunga", "Lhotse", "Gourishankar"],
      "correctIndex": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the estimated number of rivers in Nepal?",
      "answers": ["6000", "5000", "7000", "8000"],
      "correctIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of author?",
      "answers": ["pujan", "bibek", "bhugol", "dari"],
      "correctIndex": 0
    }
  ]
}
